Province of St. John the Baptist Franciscans records, 1868-1978 (bulk 1906-1965)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Series III: Catholic Organizations, 1900-1976
  - Bureau of Catholic Indian Missions: Correspondence. 1900-1976 (Box 22, Folder 1-8)
  - Bureau of Catholic Indian Missions: Correspondence regarding personnel. 1918-1934 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Bureau of Catholic Indian Missions: Religious garb in Indian schools. 1912 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Bureau of Catholic Indian Missions: Miscellaneous material, reports clippings, etc. (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Bureau of Catholic Indian Missions: Unidentified fragments. (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Sisters of the Blessed Sacrament: Correspondence. 1906-1975 (Box 23, Folder 1-2)
  - Sisters of the Blessed Sacrament: Miscellaneous material and publications. (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Sisters of the Blessed Sacrament: Mother Mary Katharine Drexel biographical material. (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Katharine Drexel, a biography by Sister Consuela Marie Duffy. Mother Katharine Drexel Guild, Sisters of the Blessed Sacrament, Cornwells Heights, Pa. 1966. Second Printing. January 1972 (Box 23)
  - Preservation Society: Early correspondence and miscellaneous material. 1907-1916 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Preservation Society: Promoters and contributors, A-Z. 1914-1917 (Box 24, Folder 2-8)
  - Catholic Church Extension Society. 1912-1939 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Catholic Medical Mission Board. 1929-1942 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Catholic Students' Mission Crusade. 1921, 1935 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Commission of Catholic Missions Among Negroes and Indians. 1926-1946 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Franciscan Indian Mission Aid. 1922 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Franciscan Missionaries of Mary: Correspondence. 1934-1950 (Box 25, Folder 6-7)
  - Franciscan Missionary Union: Correspondence, Father Dominic Calme. 1938-1948 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Franciscan Missionary Union: General correspondence. 1927-1965, 1970 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Franciscan Missionary Union: Correspondence, "venison dinners." 1933-1947 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Franciscan Missionary Union: Financial reports, miscellaneous material. (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Franciscan Sisters Convent of Our Lady of Perpetual Help, St. Louis: Correspondence. 1938-1944 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Marquette League: Historical material. (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Marquette League: Correspondence. 1906, 1926-1948 (Box 25, Folder 14-16)
  - Society for the Propagation of the Faith: Correspondence, donations, etc. 1910-1913, 1933-1946, 1961 (Box 25, Folder 17)
- Series IV: Land Records, 1868-1973
  - Correspondence: Land Commissioner of the Santa Fe Pacific Railroad Company. 1901-1962 (Box 26, Folder 1-10)
  - Correspondence: Office of the U. S. Surveyor General. 1899-1909 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: U. S. Office of Indian Affairs. 1903-1923 (Box 27, Folder 2-3)
  - Correspondence: U. S. Senator Charles Curtis. 1909-1922 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Representative Carl Hayden. 1914-1937 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Various members of Congress. 1905-1937 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Day, Charles. 1909 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Moore, Leroy O., Lawyer, Santa Fe, New Mexico. 1915-1918 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Castle Butte District, Leupp Area, and non-reservation Indian land problems. 1908-1920 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: Zuni National Forest. 1908-1915 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: Regarding Clitso Dedman and a road built on the Navajo Reservation. 1915-1921 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: Roads. 1926, 1933 (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: Miscellaneous and various. 1907-1954 (Box 27, Folder 13-14)
  - St. Michaels Mission and School Land: Historical material, plats, notes. (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - St. Michaels Mission and School Land: Correspondence and legal papers. 1899-1916, 1929-1946, 1961-1973 (Box 28, Folder 2-3)
  - Arthur Chester's Property at Tanner's Springs, Arizona: Correspondence and legal papers. 1907-1951 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Cubero and Cebolleta Boundary Dispute, New Mexico: Historical material, notes, etc. (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Cubero and Cebolleta Boundary Dispute, New Mexico: Correspondence. 1908-1911 (Box 28, Folder 6-7)
  - Pinto-Phelps Land Case, New Mexico. 1908-1926 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Indian homesteads within grant to Santa Fe Pacific Railroad Co., Arizona, T21N, Section 23: Correspondence and legal papers. 1907-1920 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Surveys, reports and statistics. (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Applications and other forms. (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Coal lands, New Mexico. 1902-1933 (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - John Osborne Property, New Mexico. 1891-1915 (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - U. S. Department of the Interior, Board of Indian Commissioners. 1914-1922 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - U. S. General Land Office, Washington D. C. 1902-1919 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - U. S. Land Office, Prescott and Phoenix, Arizona. 1901-1922 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - U. S. Land Office, Sante Fe, New Mexico. 1904-1926 (Box 29, Folder 4-5)
  - U. S. Indian Service Alloting Agent: Joseph G. Kent. 1908-1910 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - U. S. Indian Service Alloting Agent: William M. Peterson. 1908-1913 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - U. S. Indian Service Alloting Agent: A. W. Simington. 1913-1938 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - U. S. Indian Service Alloting Agent: Various. 1910-1913 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Allotments and correspondence regarding Navajo Indians and Puertecito, New Mexico. 1908, 1913 (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Allotment Plats (townships). (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Navajo Allotment Book. 1913-1931? (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Allotment lists, notes, etc. (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - "Land Index." (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - "Treaty with the Navajo," (various items). 1868 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Land Scrip Companies. 1905-1914 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Father Anselm Weber: Miscellaneous material on water development. 1908-1909, 1920 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Father Anselm Weber: "Statement" on early surveys. September 28, 1914 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Pollock Scrip applications for lands north of Williams, Arizona. 1920-1921 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - "Extension of the Reservation." 1924 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - J. C. Morgan and Navajo Land Acquisition. 1927-1939, 1948 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - H. J. Hagerman, Special Commissioner to Investigate Navajo Land Situation. 1923-1932 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Leases, Arizona. (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Leases, New Mexico. (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous material and notes. (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Grazing Case: Frank Dugan v. Peter Paquette. 1916 (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Grazing Case: U. S. v. Henry and Martha Bigman. 1938 (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Grazing Case: U. S. v. various Indians, Salt Lake City, Utah. 1941 (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - Grazing: Miscellaneous material. (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - Timber on the Navajo Reservation: Miscellaneous material. (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - Farmer, Malcom F.: "Final Report on the Territory and Territorial Boundaries of the Navajo Indians." Also supplementary material. 1951, 1952 (Box 30, Folder 17)
  - Lynch Estate: Correspondence. 1905-1926 (Box 31, Folder 1-2)
  - Lynch Estate: Legal papers. (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Lynch Estate: Various banks. (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Lynch Estate: McKinley County Bank, Gallup, New Mexico. 1907-1914 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Lynch Estate: Miscellaneous financial records and notes. (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Lynch Estate: Letterbook. May 1906-February 1907 (Box 31)
  - Government Publications: U. S. Soil Conservation Service, Navajo District: "Sub-Watershed Plan, Land Management Unit No. 5, Navajo District Region 8." 1937? (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Government Publications: Land allotments to Indians. 1887-1918 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Government Publications: Use of National Forests. 1907-1909 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Government Publications: Homestead Entries, Oil and Gas Leases, Mineral Surveys, etc. 1907-1952 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Government Publications: Grazing. 1914, 1937-1944, 1950 (Box 32, Folder 5-6)
- Series V: Province of St. John the Baptist, 1897-1976
  - Office of the Provincial: General correspondence. 1897, 1902-1921 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Office of the Provincial: Correspondence Father Edmund Klein. 1921-1927 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Office of the Provincial: Correspondence Father Urban Freundt. 1927-1933 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Office of the Provincial: Correspondence Father Maurice Ripperger. 1933-1939 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Office of the Provincial: Correspondence Father Adalbert Rolfes. 1939-1944 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Office of the Provincial: Correspondence Father Romuald Mollaum. 1945-1951 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Office of the Provincial: General correspondence. 1951-1976 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Office of the Provincial: Financial correspondence Father Adalbert Rolfes. 1935-1939 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Office of the Provincial: Financial correspondence Father Theodore Hasselbrock. 1939-1946 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Navajo Mission Board: Meetings. 1924-1928 (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Board of Franciscan Mission of the Southwest/Franciscan Mission Board: Meetings. 1931-1932 (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - Navaho Missionary Fathers/Navajo Missionaries: Meetings. 1945-1959 (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - Navaho Board. 1960-1969? (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - Navaho Council. 1970-1971 (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - Office of the Provincial: China Missions reports. 1945/46, 1946/47 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Office of the Provincial: [Circular Newsletter]. 1908-1972 (Box 34, Folder 2-6)
  - Publications: Catalogus Fratrum. 1928, 1933, 1939, 1946, 1956, 1967 (Box 35, Folder 1-2)
  - Publications: Tabula Definitionis. 1926-1928, 1934, 1947-1963 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Publications: Provincial Directory. 1934-1972 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Publications: Personnel Directory, Cincinnati Franciscans in the United States. 1973, 1974, 1976 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous publications and directories. (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Publications: Navajo Missionary Newsletter, St. Michaels Mission, vol. 2, #1, 3, vol. 3, #5. Fall 1959, Mid-Winter 1970, 1971 (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Publications: "Selected Bibliography of the American Indian." A collection at the Motherhouse of the Sisters of the Blessed Sacrament, Cornwells Heights, Pa. 1970 (Box 35, Folder 8)
- Series VI: Franciscan Fathers, 1902-1975
  - Fund Raising: Appeal form letters. 1932-1967 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Fund Raising: Answers to appeals. 1933-1935 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Fund Raising: Benefit recital for organ at Ft. Defiance Mission Church. April 1, 1934 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Fund Raising: Commercial firms. 1934-1937 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - American Red Cross. 1940-1950 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - "Protestants Correspondence," and related materials. 1902-1944 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - "Dutch Reformed Missions," clippings from The Banner. 1912-1914 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous meetings and conferences. 1928-1975 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Awatovi: Correspondence and related material regarding a Hopi Pueblo Ruin. 1937-1946 (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Hopi Mission including correspondence with various Catholic organizations and government officials. 1905-1911 (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - "Papago Missions." 1930-1939, 1956-1958 (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - Radio Programs, KFH, Wichita, Kansas. 1939-1940 (Box 36, Folder 12)
  - Order of Friars Minor: Constitutions. (Box 36, Folder 13)
  - Baptism policy. (Box 36, Folder 14)
  - Mass Book. (Box 36, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous material, some undated and not fully identified. (Box 36, Folder 16)
  - Church Doctrine and the Navajo: Apostleship of Prayer Register. St. Michaels, Reverend Marcellus Troester, Director. 1921-1923? (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Church Doctrine and the Navajo: Baptism, Communion, Confirmation, Marriage, Extreme Unction. (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Church Doctrine and the Navajo: Prayers, music, Ten Commandments, etc. (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Church Doctrine and the Navajo: Sermons. (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Church Doctrine and the Navajo: Catechism. (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Church Doctrine and the Navajo: Stories of various saints. (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Church Doctrine and the Navajo: "Navaho-English Catechism with Commentary." 1953 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Church Doctrine and the Navajo: "History of the New Testament." Notebooks no. 1 and 3 (in Navajo). (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Church Doctrine and the Navajo: "Bible History." Translated by Father Leopold Ostermann. 1947 (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Church Doctrine and the Navajo: "The Rosary in Navajo," by Father Cormac Antram. 1958 (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - Church Doctrine and the Navajo: "Navajo Harmony Way and the Way of Christ." A tentative outline. July 23, 1971 (Box 37, Folder 11)
- Series VII: Catholic Church, 1895-1975
  - Diocese of Tucson: Bishop Henry Granjon correspondence. 1900-1921 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Diocese of Tucson: Bishop Daniel J. Gercke correspondence. 1923-1946 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Diocese of Tucson: Bishop Daniel J. Gercke communications. 1928-1940 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Diocese of Gallup: Bishop Bernard T. Espelage biographical material. (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Diocese of Gallup: Bishop Bernard T. Espelage correspondence. 1910 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Diocese of Gallup: Communication from various bishops. 1942-1975 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Diocese of Gallup: Cathedral of the Sacred Heart, Gallup. (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Diocese of Gallup: Father Emanuel Trockur's Articles About. 1961-1963 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Archbishop of Santa Fe J. B. Pitaval correspondence. 1910-1920 (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Various Archbishops of Sante Fe. (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - Missions in the Southwest (lists, sites, etc.). (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - Catholic Indian Center, Gallup, New Mexico. (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - St. Mary Hospital, Gallup, New Mexico. 1910-1934 (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - Reverend George J. Julliard correspondence. 1895-1897, 1900, 1907 (Box 38, Folder 14)
- Series VIII: United States Government Offices and Indian Organizations, 1905-1971
  - U. S. Indian Service: Navajo Indian Agency, Ft. Defiance, Arizona, Annual Report. 1905/06 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - U. S. Indian Service: Pueblo Bonita Agency, S. F. Stracher, Superintendent. 1910-1922 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - U. S. Indian Service: Various personnel matters. 1910-1921 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - U. S. Office of Indian Affairs, Navajo Service, Window Rock Agency, Arizona. 1937-1952 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - U. S. Office of Indian Affairs, Missionary Conference, Window Rock, Arizona. October 28-29, 1946 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - U. S. Department of the Interior, Post-war Resources Institute, Washington D. C. November 5-9, 1945 (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Superintendent W. T. Shelton: Correspondence and other materials. 1907-1971 (Box 39, Folder 7)
    "Trouble at Shiprock." Includes correspondence of Laurence Davis in 1971 regarding this incident.
  - Superintendent James Stewart: Correspondence and other materials. 1945-1957 (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Scott, General Hugh L.: Correspondence including correspondence with Father Anselm Weber, Chee Dodge Bizhoshi, etc. 1912-1927 (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - Conference on Navajo Off-Reservation Employment, Gallup, New Mexico. March 13-14, 1952 (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - Navajo Uprising. 1913 (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - Proposed Central Navajo Agency. 1934 (Box 39, Folder 12)
  - Radio broadcasts from KTGM, Window Rock, Arizona. 1938-1939 (Box 39, Folder 13)
  - Drum Beats, vol. 1-3, Navajo Agency, Window Rock, Arizona. (Box 39, Folder 14)
  - Society of American Indians: Miscellaneous material. 1913 (Box 39, Folder 15)
  - National Congress of American Indians: Miscellaneous material. 1948-1956 (Box 39, Folder 16)
- Series IX: Indian Education, 1908-1972
  - U. S. Office of Indian Affairs: Religious instruction in schools. 1910-1949 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - U. S. Indian Service/Office of Indian Affairs, Ft. Defiance Agency: Chiefly regarding religions instruction in schools. 1908-1922 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - U. S. Indian Service Indian School, Albuquerque, New Mexico. 1908-1922 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence regarding Superintendent Peter Paquette, Ft. Defiance, Arizona and a religious controversy. 1916-1924 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Parents' Authorization for Religious Instruction. 1913-1930, 1951 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - "Resolution of the Catholic Missionary Group on the Navaho Indian Reservation," regarding Indian education. 1946 (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Lists of schools, enrollment, personnel, reports. 1921-1954 (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Indian Students. 1933-1951 (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - Intermountain Indian School, Brigham City Utah, miscellaneous publications. 1949-1954, 1972 (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Intermountain Indian School, Brigham City Utah, Indian Service Summer School. 1951 (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Ute Mountain Indian School, Towaoc, Colorado. 1924-1933 (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous government publications: Schools. (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - Government publications: School Curricula. 1926, 1945 (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous clippings. (Box 40, Folder 14)
- Series X: Navaho Indians, 1899-1975
  - Issues and Topics, 1899-1975
    - Health and welfare cases. 1935-1957 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Navajo Marriage: General correspondence. 1910, 1928-1956 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Navajo Marriage: Individual problems and records. 1900-1962 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Navajo Marriage: Forms, laws, articles, notes, etc. (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Military Service: Miscellaneous correspondence and records. 1938-1968 (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - Military Service: Halliday, Tom Bahe, military allotment for daughter. 1942-1945 (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - Military Service: Judy, John K, military service, death, etc. 1944-1948 (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - Military Service: Murphy, Benjamin J., military allotment for mother. 1944 (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - Military Service: Nalwood, Hoska, veteran insurance policy. 1943-1956 (Box 41, Folder 9)
    - Loans. 1916-1947 (Box 41, Folder 10)
    - Prisoners. 1899-1961 (Box 41, Folder 11)
    - Off-Reservation employment. 1911, 1940-1942 (Box 41, Folder 12)
    - Dalgai (Navaho) and the Frank Dugan murder at Cross Canyon, Arizona. 1922-1925, 1943 (Box 41, Folder 13)
    - Mistreatment of As-Ton-Pia, a Navajo woman, by Agency Officials. 1932 (Box 41, Folder 14)
    - Gorman, Frank: Accident and insurance problem. 1953-1954 (Box 41, Folder 15)
    - Liquor on the reservation. 1902-1970 (Box 41, Folder 16)
    - Requests for information regarding baptisms, marriage records, etc. 1912-1975 (Box 41, Folder 17)
    - Miscellaneous missionary material. (Box 41, Folder 18)
  - Navaho Individuals, 1905-1945
    - Dodge, Henry "Chee": biographical material. (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Dodge, Henry "Chee": Miscellaneous letters to, from and about. 1905-1945 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Dodge, Henry "Chee": Financial papers. 1908-1915, 1920 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Mitchells, Charles and Frank: Biographical material. (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Murphy, Pat: Biographical material. (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - Murphy, Pat: Correspondence. 1936-1942 (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - Taliman, Henry: Biographical material. (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - Walker, Frank: Biographical material. (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - Walker, Frank: Correspondence. 1916, 1938-1945 (Box 42, Folder 9)
    - Wauneka, Annie Dodge: Biographical material. (Box 42, Folder 10)
    - Silow Bitsocie "Slim Policeman": Biographical sketch by Will Evans. 1939 (Box 42, Folder 11)
  - Legislation and Government Publications Regarding Indians, 1934-1962
    - Legislation: Wheeler-Howard Bill, H. R. 7902 and S. 2755. 1934 (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Legislation: Wheeler-Howard Bill, comments, analysis, etc. (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Legislation: Wheeler-Howard Bill, Navajo Tribal Council Minutes. March 12-13, 1934 (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - Legislation: Navajo and Hopi Rehabilitation Bill, S. 1407. 1949 (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Government Publications: Appropriations for the Bureau of Indian Affairs. 1907-1948 (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - Government Publications: "The Indian Problem." (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Government Publications: Medical Care for Indians. 1916-1962 (Box 43, Folder 7)
      Includes letters and articles by Frederick L. Hoffman to Father Anselm Weber.
    - Government Publications: Indian Reservation, general conditions, etc. (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - Government Publications: Law and Order. 1937 (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - Navajo Tribal Council, 1923-1974
    - U. S. Office of Indian Affairs: Regulations, administrative reorganization, etc. 1923-1936 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - "With the Reorganization Committee of the Navajo Tribal Council, 1936-1937", by Father Berard Haile? April 19, 1937 (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Navajo Tribal Council: Photos, miscellaneous historical notes by Father Emanuel and others. (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Navajo Tribal Council: Miscellaneous material. (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Navajo Tribal Council: Proceedings of the meeting. March 1-4, 1954 (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Navajo Tribal Council: Record of the Advisory Committee. November 19-20, 1964 (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - Navajo Tribal Council: Resolutions and miscellaneous material regarding labor. 1957-1958 (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - Navajo Tribal Council: Miscellaneous resolutions. 1940-1962 (Box 44, Folder 8)
    - Navajo Tribal Council: Tribal budget. 1951-1952 (Box 44, Folder 9)
    - Navajo Tribal Council: Chairman Paul Jones, miscellaneous material. 1957-1961 (Box 44, Folder 10)
    - Navajo Tribal Council: Chairman Raymond Naki, miscellaneous material. 1963-1974 (Box 44, Folder 11)
    - Navajo Constitution and By-laws (proposed). 1953-1953 (Box 44, Folder 12)
    - Norman Littell, Navajo General Council: Clippings, notes, miscellaneous material. 1961-1968 (Box 44, Folder 13)
    - Sleight, Frederick W.: "Navajo Traditional Geography Studies, Part 1." Navajo Cardinal Mountain Identification. (Box 44, Folder 14)
  - Articles about Navajo Indians, 1935-1968
    - Currie, Edgar: "A Program of Self-Improvement for the Navajo." 1949? (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Hancock, Sibyl: Correspondence regarding a legendary "Straw Man" of the Navajos. 1968 (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - Kirk, Ruth: Articles, etc., about Navajo Indians. 1940-1948 (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - The Pipeliner, a publication of the El Paso Natural Gas Company. August 1958 (Box 45, Folder 4)
      This issue features Navajo Indians.
    - Navaho language items: Miscellaneous songs, stories lessons, etc. (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - Navajo Religion: Articles by various authors. (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - "The Apaches of Navajo," a series of articles from St. Anthony Messenger. August 1935-October 1936 (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - Ostermann, Leopold, "Grammatical Notes of the Navajo Language." (Box 45, Folder 8)
- Series XI: Estates, Guardianships and Wills, 1929-1967
  - Estates: Adakai, Chester. 1945-1947 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Estates: Gorman, Eli. 1953-1954 (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Estates: Silversmith, Ted (financial papers). 1956-1960 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Estates: Silversmith, Ted (personal papers). (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Estates: Silversmith, Ted (insurance). (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Estates: Williams, Henry. 1949-1950 (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Estates: Various. (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Estate Bequests: McGraill, Anna. 1929-1937 (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Estate Bequests: Various. (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - Guardianship: Silvership, June. 1963-1967 (Box 46, Folder 10)
  - Guardianship: Silversmith, Ted, Jr. and Rose. 1962-1964 (Box 46, Folder 11)
  - Guardianship: Six, Willie. 1955-1957 (Box 46, Folder 12)
  - Guardianship: Various. (Box 46, Folder 13)
  - Last Wills and Testaments (Indian). (Box 46, Folder 14)
- Series XII: FatherEmanuel Trockur, 1924-1977
  - Biographical Material, 1963-1970
    - Biographical Material: General. (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - Biographical Material: Medical. (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - Biographical Material: Michael F. Trockur (brother). (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - Photographs. (Box 47, Folder 4)